Guide to the Kings County Historic Records Microfilm Collection BCMS.0047
Brooklyn Collection
Kings County Historic Records Microfilm Collection
1645-1961
1650-1900
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0047
3.89 Linear Feet in 62 reels in 11 boxes.
Microfilm reels showing a variety of government records, maps and histories concerning Kings County, New York from 1645-1961.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to preservation concerns, these reels are kept in cold storage and must be brought up to room temperature before use. Researchers must use gloves when handling the microfilm.
Existence and Location of Originals
Most (but not all) of the original documents are housed at the New York City Municipal Archives: Old Town Records, Collection MSS0004 - RG 096. Old Town records.
Existence and Location of Copies
Other microfilm copies are housed and and available digitally online at the New York City Municipal Archives: Microfilm of Kings County Old Town records circa 1640 to 1895. Accession ACC-1988-122. RG 096. Old Town records. An index of the microfilm is available at the NYC Municipal Archives.
Historical Note
Kings County was settled by Europeans beginning in 1636 with a series of land grants provided by the Dutch West India Company. In 1638 the Company purchased a large tract of land in the area of present day Williamsburg, Bushwick and Greenpoint; beginning a series of land transfers that would turn the Eastern shoreline, then nearly the whole of Kings County to European control by the late 1640s.
As land grants continued to be doled out, small settlements including Midwout and New Amersfoort began to emerge under the general governance of the Director of New Amsterdam. This changed in 1645 when a group living in the English settlement of Gravesend petitioned Director Willem Kieft for a town charter. The Dutch West India Company quickly implemented a policy granting town charters to Breuckelen (1646), Flatlands/New Amersfoort (1647), Flatbush/Midwout (1652), New Utrecht (1657) and Bushwick/Boswick (1661). With the exception of Gravesend, the towns' people were responsible for nominating a town magistrate, who was then approved and supervised by Director Peter Stuyvesant (appointed 1647).
In 1664 the English gained control of New Amsterdam, renaming the area New York. On November 29, 1683 the six original towns were established as Kings County, serving as an administrative arm of New York colony. The first acts of county government consisted of various courts and a county clerk to maintain records. Beginning in the early 1700s a Board of Supervisors was established by delegates from each town, who would meet to discuss county issues and appoint various commissioners including County Road Commissioners responsible for various highways across Kings County. In addition to County government, each town was responsible for electing officials to oversee local matters such as the development of new roads and rules governing common woodlands. New offices were created as needed.
The population of Kings County grew rapidly from 1800-1830, especially in the towns of Brooklyn and Bushwick. In 1816 a small area in the town of Brooklyn extending from the East River to today's Borough Hall was chartered as the village of Brooklyn. Residents of the town of Bushwick followed in 1827 with the creation of the village of Williamsburgh. These villages elected trustees responsible for overseeing the growth and daily concerns of the villages, including the paving of roads and construction of new housing.
In 1833 the village and town of Brooklyn sent an appeal to the New York State Legislature for a city charter, which after several delays was granted in 1834. The remaining towns were slowly annexed to the city of Brooklyn beginning with Bushwick in 1854 and followed by the village of Williamsburgh, which existed briefly as the city of Williamsburg before annexation in 1855. Williamsburg was followed by New Lots (1886), Flatbush (1894), Gravesend (1894), New Utrecht (1894) and Flatlands (1896). The city of Brooklyn was consolidated into greater New York on January 1, 1898.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 62 microfilm reels showing a variety of documents concerning Kings County, New York from the mid-17th century to the late 19th century. The earliest records include town meeting minutes, births of enslaved persons, health records, deeds and court records for the towns of Bushwick, Gravesend, Flatbush, Flatlands and New Utrecht. Records for the village of Williamsburgh begin in 1832. A few records appear in Dutch with an English translation on the opposite page. Some records are typed and handwritten copies made in the 1920s and 1940s.
Records beginning circa 1830 show the towns' transition from rural farmland to smaller, gridded lots. Maps overlay new lots with boundary lines and conveyance dates of original farms. Detailed street papers and sewer plans appear with short histories of many County roads including Kings Highway.
Several reels also contain thesis and term papers for students attending the James A. Kelly Institute for Historical Studies at St. Francis College in the late 1950s and early 1960s. The papers cover a broad range of topics including education, law enforcement and manufacturing in Brooklyn. Profiles of prominent citizens and histories of cultural institutions are also covered.
Access
Open to users without restriction.
Provenance
This collection was acquired from the James A. Kelly Institute for Historical Studies at St. Francis College, most likely after the Institute's 1988 closure.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by reel number. Records are listed under each reel in order of appearance.
Related Materials
Center for Brooklyn History holds the following related materials:
Documents relative to the colonial history of the state of New York. Weed, Parsons and Co. 1853-1857.
Flint, Martha Bockée. Long Island before the Revolution; a colonial study. I. J. Friedman. 1967.
Innes, John H. New Amsterdam and its people; studies, social and topographical, of the town under Dutch and early English rule. I.J. Friedman. c1969.
Jaray, Cornell. Historic chronicles of New Amsterdam, colonial New York, and early Long Island. I.J. Friedman. 1968.
Ment, David. The Shaping of a City, A Brief History of Brooklyn. Brooklyn Educational & Cultural Alliance. 1979.
Reynolds, Samuel. A history of the city of Williamsburgh, N.Y.: containing a succinct account of its early settlement, rapid growth and prosperous condition, with many other important and interesting facts connected with the same. J.C. Gandar. 1852.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); Flatlands (New York, N.Y.); Gravesend (New York, N.Y.); Kings County (N.Y.); New Lots (New York, N.Y.); New Utrecht (New York, N.Y.)
- Reel 1
  - The Descendants of Wolphert Gerretse Van Kouwenhoven Through His Eldest Son Gerret Wolphertsen Van Couwenhoven, circa 1650-1850 (Reel 1)
  - The Descendants of Wolphert Gerretse Van Kouwenhoven Through His Son Jacob Wolphertsen Van Couwenhoven, circa 1650-1850 (Reel 1)
  - The Descendants of Wolphert Gerretse Van Kouwenhoven Through His Youngest Son Peter Wolphertsen Van Cowenhoven, circa 1650-1850 (Reel 1)
  - The Descendants of Wolphert Gerretse Van Kouwenhoven Through His Three Sons Gerret, Jacob and Peter Together With Their Spouses, circa 1650-1850 (Reel 1)
  - Slave Holders in Kings County, Flatbush, Certified Births of Negro Children, 1799-1826 (Reel 1)
  - A True List of All the Slaves of the Township of Newuytreght (New Utrecht) in Kings County, 1800-1830 (Reel 1)
  - Slaves Register and Record of Personal Mortgages, 1799-1830 (Reel 1)
  - New Utrecht Town Records, Town Meetings, Deeds, 1659-1831 (Reel 1)
- Reel 2
  - Van Kouwen, Convor Items Abstracted in 1938 From Manuscript by Tunis G. Bergen, circa 1650-1790 (Reel 2)
  - Index, Probate of Wills, 1850-1890 (Reel 2)
  - Bushwick Town Records. History, Deeds, Road Records, Births of Slaves, etc., 1660-1825 (Reel 2)
    General
    In Dutch and English
  - Brooklyn Town Meeting Book, 1785-1823 (Reel 2)
- Reel 3
  - Old Road Abstracts Index, circa 1650-1800 (Reel 3)
  - Maps Without Histories, 1646-1876 (Reel 3)
  - Old Road Abstracts, First Division, circa 1695-1852 (Reel 3)
  - Historical Notes, Flatlands, circa 1670-1850 (Reel 3)
- Reel 4
  - Historical Notes, Flatlands, circa 1650-1900 (Reel 4)
  - Historical Notes, Flatbush, circa 1670-1900 (Reel 4)
  - Historical Notes, New Utrecht, circa 1650-1900 (Reel 4)
  - Historical Notes, Gravesend, circa 1650-1900 (Reel 4)
- Reel 5
  - Copies of Deeds and Patents in Secretary of State's Office, circa 1630-1700 (Reel 5)
  - Patents, circa 1654-1680 (Reel 5)
  - Wills Volume I, 1658-1890 (Reel 5)
- Reel 6
  - Wills Volume 2, 1653-1876 (Reel 6)
  - Wills Volume 3, 1653-1895 (Reel 6)
  - Un-Recorded Deeds, Volume I, 1647-1887 (Reel 6)
- Reel 7
  - Un-Recorded Deeds, Volume 2, circa 1650-1890 (Reel 7)
  - Un-Recorded Deeds, Volume 3, circa 1650-1890 (Reel 7)
  - Un-Recorded Deeds, Volume 4, circa 1650-1890 (Reel 7)
  - Un-Recorded Deeds, Volume 5, circa 1650-1890 (Reel 7)
- Reel 8
  - Un-Recorded Deeds, Volume 5, circa 1650-1890 (Reel 8)
  - Book 700, Bushwick Town Records, History, Deeds, Births of Slaves, 1660-1825 (Reel 8)
  - Book 601, Williamsburgh Town Clerk's Book, 1842-1855 (Reel 8)
- Reel 9
  - Book 682, Williamsburgh Town Records, 1832-1837 (Reel 9)
  - Kings County Court and Road Records, Volume 1, 1692-1825 (Reel 9)
  - Kings County Court and Road Records, Volume 2, 1668-1766 (Reel 9)
- Reel 10
  - Gravesend Town Records, Book 1, 1645-1653 (Reel 10)
  - Gravesend Town Records, Book 2, 1653-1705 (Reel 10)
  - Gravesend Town Records, Book 3, 1656-1705 (Reel 10)
  - Gravesend Town Records, Book 4, 1662-1699 (Reel 10)
  - Gravesend Town Records, Book 5, 1672-1686 (Reel 10)
  - Gravesend Town Records, Book 6, 1645-1701 (Reel 10)
  - Gravesend Town Records, Book 7, 1699-1872 (Reel 10)
- Reel 11
  - Gravesend Town Records, Miscellaneous, 1664-1834 (Reel 11)
  - Gravesend Miscellaneous Papers, Volume 1, 1724-1896 (Reel 11)
    Audits, Bonds, Commons Lands, Elections, Excise, Fire Department, Gas and Electric
  - Gravesend Miscellaneous Papers, Volume 2, 1800-1894 (Reel 11)
    Health, Highway, Jurors Lists, Oyster Permits, Police Commissioner, Rail Road, School Trustees
- Reel 12
  - Gravesend Miscellaneous Papers, Volume 3, 1823-1894 (Reel 12)
    Schools, Sewers
  - Gravesend Street Papers, A-G, circa 1880-1900 (Reel 12)
  - Gravesend Street Papers, H-Z, circa 1880-1900 (Reel 12)
- Reel 13
  - Gravesend Street Papers, H-Z (continued), circa 1880-1900 (Reel 13)
  - Gravesend Town Meeting, Town Board Papers, 1736-1894 (Reel 13)
  - Gravesend Common Lands Papers, 1852-1894 (Reel 13)
- Reel 14
  - Gravesend Board of Health Minutes, 1884-1886 (Reel 14)
  - Gravesend 312-315-316, Town Board Minutes, 1884-1894 (Reel 14)
  - Gravesend 313, Town Meeting, Town Board Minutes, 1873-1894 (Reel 14)
- Reel 15
  - Gravesend 314, Town Meetings, Town Board Minutes, 1873-1883 (Reel 15)
  - Gravesend 317, School Accounts, Births of Slaves, 1830-1843, 1799-1819 (Reel 15)
  - Gravesend 318, School District #1 Records, 1857-1894 (Reel 15)
  - Gravesend 319-320 Record of Troops, 1861-1865 (Reel 15)
  - Gravesend 321, Common Law Trustees Minutes, 1880-1894 (Reel 15)
  - Gravesend 323, Board of Health Minutes, 1889-1890 (Reel 15)
- Reel 16
  - Gravesend 323, Board of Health Minutes, 1887-1889 (Reel 16)
  - Gravesend 324, Board of Health Minutes, 1890-1893 (Reel 16)
  - Gravesend 325, Board of Health Minutes, 1893 (Reel 16)
- Reel 17
  - Gravesend 326-327-328-330-331, Sewer Construction Accounts, 1885-1895 (Reel 17)
  - Gravesend 329, Board of Health Sewer Construction Records, Volume 2, 1885-1887 (Reel 17)
  - Gravesend 329, Board of Health Sewer Construction Records, Volume 2, 1885-1887 (Reel 17)
- Reel 18
  - Gravesend 333, Board of Health Account with Town Treasury, 1886-1889 (Reel 18)
  - Gravesend Cash Book Journal, 1886-1890 (Reel 18)
  - Gravesend 335, Sewer Construction Record, 1887-1889 (Reel 18)
- Reel 19
  - Gravesend 337, Town Auditor Minutes, 1879-1894 (Reel 19)
  - Gravesend 338, Street Invoice Book, 1885-1886 (Reel 19)
  - Gravesend 340-342, Street Sewer Bonds, 1886-1893 (Reel 19)
  - Gravesend 344, Health Board Minutes, 1886-1887 (Reel 19)
  - Gravesend 344, Health Board Minutes, 1887 (Reel 19)
- Reel 20
  - New Utrecht Miscellaneous Papers, Volume 1, 1796-1894 (Reel 20)
    Minutes, Military, Notice of Stray Animals, Drift Timber, Supervisor Accounts, Taxes, Water Company, School Papers
  - New Utrecht Miscellaneous Papers, Volume 2, 1840-1894 (Reel 20)
    Audits, Excise Commissioners, Fence Viewers, Fire Department, Board of Health, Jury Lists, Drainage, Police Department, Flagging
  - New Utrecht Miscellaneous Papers, Volume 3, 1801-1895 (Reel 20)
    Bath Beach Sewer, Street Improvements, Highways
- Reel 21
  - New Utrecht Highway Commissioners Report, 1833-1894 (Reel 21)
  - New Utrecht 2000-2002, Town Records, History and Deeds, 1659-1831 (Reel 21)
  - Flatlands Bergen Papers, 1677-1849 (Reel 21)
- Reel 22
  - New Utrecht School Papers, 1827-1894 (Reel 22)
  - New Utrecht Street Papers Volume 1, A-B, circa 1880-1895 (Reel 22)
  - New Utrecht Street Papers, Volume 2, C-E, circa 1880-1895 (Reel 22)
- Reel 23
  - New Utrecht Street Papers, Volume 2, C-F, circa 1880-1895 (Reel 23)
  - New Utrecht Street Papers, Volume 3, F, circa 1880-1895 (Reel 23)
  - New Utrecht Street Papers, Volume 4, G-R, circa 1880-1895 (Reel 23)
- Reel 24
  - New Utrecht Street Papers, Volume 4, G-R, circa 1880-1895 (Reel 24)
  - New Utrecht Street Papers, Volume 5, S, circa 1880-1895 (Reel 24)
  - New Utrecht Street Papers, Volume 6, T-Z, circa 1880-1895 (Reel 24)
  - New Utrecht Town Meeting Minutes, Book 204-207, 1793-1829 (Reel 24)
- Reel 25
  - Flatbush Book 100, Liber A, Deeds, Wills, circa 1670-1700 (Reel 25)
  - Flatbush Book 101, Liber AA, Deeds, 1676-1682 (Reel 25)
  - Flatbush Book 102, Liber B, Deeds, 1700-1708 (Reel 25)
- Reel 26
  - Flatbush Book 1003, Liber B, Court Minutes and Deeds, circa 1650-1665 (Reel 26)
  - Flatbush Book 1004, Liber C, Deeds, circa 1665-1700 (Reel 26)
  - Flatbush Book 1005, Liber D, Court Minutes, Volume 1, circa 1665-1670 (Reel 26)
- Reel 27
  - Flatbush Book 1005, Liber D, Court Minutes, Volume 2, 1669-1670 (Reel 27)
  - Flatbush Book 1005, Liber D, Court Minutes, Volume 2, circa 1670-1680 (Reel 27)
  - Flatbush Book 106, Town Accounts, Town Meetings, 1663-1680, 1701-1762 (Reel 27)
- Reel 28
  - Flatbush Book 107, Court and Slave Records, Town Meetings, 1679-1819 (Reel 28)
  - Flatbush Book 108, Town Records, 1819-1851 (Reel 28)
  - Flatbush Book 109, Town Board Minutes, 1875-1882 (Reel 28)
  - Flatbush Books 110-116, Supervisors Annual Reports, 1885-1894 (Reel 28)
- Reel 29
  - Photos, Prints (negative images), circa 1900-1950 (Reel 29)
    Bridges, Buildings, Churches, Transportation, Schools
- Reel 30
  - Photos, Prints (negative images), circa 1900-1950 (Reel 30)
    Coney Island, Hospitals, Residences, Revolutionary War
- Reel 31
  - Old Road Abstracts, First Division, circa 1650-1830 (Reel 31)
- Reel 32
  - Photographs and Prints, circa 1920-1950 (Reel 32)
    Coney Island, Schools, Street Scenes
  - Old Road Abstracts, First Division, circa 1650-1830 (Reel 32)
  - New Utrecht Town Meeting Minutes, Book 208-241, 1827-1894 (Reel 32)
  - New Utrecht, Book 209-211-213, Slaves and Strays Record, 1795-1822 (Reel 32)
  - New Utrecht 203, Election Returns, 1799-1822 (Reel 32)
  - New Utrecht 212 and 217, Road Records, circa 1700-1860 (Reel 32)
  - Photographs and Prints (Reel 32)
    Parks, Hospitals, Schools, Street Scenes
- Reel 33
  - New Utrecht 215 and 218, Supervisor Accounts, 1823-1870 (Reel 33)
  - New Utrecht 216 and 221, Supervisor Accounts, 1875-1894 (Reel 33)
  - New Utrecht 220, 224, 230, Supervisor Accounts, Bonds, 1835-1900 (Reel 33)
  - New Utrecht 222-223, Supervisor Accounts, Streets, 1885-1894 (Reel 33)
- Reel 34
  - Photos and Prints, circa 1900-1920 (Reel 34)
    Churches, Coney Island, Houses, Meeting Notices, Street Scenes
- Reel 35
  - New Utrecht 225, Oaths and Bonds, 1877-1893 (Reel 35)
  - New Utrecht 226, Oaths, 1885-1894 (Reel 35)
  - New Utrecht 227, Drainage Assessments, circa 1860-1870 (Reel 35)
  - New Utrecht 228, Chattel Mortgages, 1850-1880 (Reel 35)
  - New Utrecht 229, Chattel Mortgages, 1875-1892 (Reel 35)
  - New Utrecht 233-235, Record of Troops, 1851-1865 (Reel 35)
- Reel 36
  - New Utrecht 237, Sewer Commissioner's Journal, Bath Beach, 1889-1894 (Reel 36)
  - New Utrecht 239, Commissioner's Journal, Bath Beach Improvement, 1894-1895 (Reel 36)
  - New Utrecht 242-263, Assessment Rolls, 1830-1854 (Reel 36)
  - New Utrecht 264-268, Assessment Rolls, 1855-1859 (Reel 36)
- Reel 37
  - New Utrecht 268-273, Assessment Rolls, circa 1830-1865 (Reel 37)
  - New Utrecht 2074-2077, 1866-1869 (Reel 37)
- Reel 38
  - Flatbush Street Papers, Volume 1, A-D, 1855-1895 (Reel 38)
  - Flatbush Street Papers, Volume 2, E-K, 1855-1895 (Reel 38)
- Reel 39
  - Flatbush Street Papers, Volume 3, L-M, circa 1855-1895 (Reel 39)
  - Flatbush Street Papers, Volume 4, N-R, circa 1855-1895 (Reel 39)
  - Flatbush Street Papers, Volume 5, R-Z, circa 1855-1895 (Reel 39)
- Reel 40
  - Flatbush Miscellaneous, Volume 1, 1652-1708 (Reel 40)
  - Issue of Country Life in America, 1908 (June) (Reel 40)
  - Flatbush Miscellaneous, Volume 2, 1658-1799 (Reel 40)
  - Flatbush Book 117-121, School District 3, Tax Lists, 1879-1882 (Reel 40)
- Reel 41
  - Flatbush Book 121-122, School District 3, Tax Lists, 1883-1884 (Reel 41)
  - Flatbush 123-125, 127, 130, School Accounts Census, 1875-1893 (Reel 41)
  - Flatbush Book 131, Justice's Court Records, 1887-1892 (Reel 41)
  - Flatbush Book 132, Board of Health Minutes, 1874-1886 (Reel 41)
  - Re-Mounted Maps, 1899-1907 (Reel 41)
- Reel 42
  - Flatbush Book 134, Chattel Mortgages, 1883-1890 (Reel 42)
  - Flatbush Book 136-137, State Census, 1845 (Reel 42)
  - Flatbush Book 138-139, Improvement Board, Cash Book and Ledger, 1872-1894 (Reel 42)
  - Flatbush Book 140-143, Highway Commissioner's and Treasurer's Receipts, 1869-1888 (Reel 42)
  - Flatbush Book 144-148, Highway Commissioner's and Treasurer's Receipts, 1874-1893 (Reel 42)
- Reel 43
  - Flatbush Book 148, Highway Commissioner's and Treasurer's Receipts, 1893 (Reel 43)
  - Flatbush Book 149, Highway Commissioner's Minutes, 1877-1884 (Reel 43)
  - Flatbush Books 150-152, Highway Commissioner's and Treasurer's Account, 1859-1889 (Reel 43)
  - Flatbush Books 153-155, Highway Commissioner's, Treasurer's Account Crosswalks, Ocean Avenue, 1872-1892 (Reel 43)
  - Flatbush Book 160, Improvement Board Minutes, 1872-1875 (Reel 43)
- Reel 44
  - Flatbush Book 160, Improvement Board Minutes, 1872-1875 (Reel 44)
  - Flatbush Book 161, Improvement Board Minutes, 1885-1894 (Reel 44)
  - Flatbush Books 162-163, Assessment Sales, Treasurer's Book, 1874-1893 (Reel 44)
  - Flatbush Book 164, Assessment Sales, Clerk's Book, 1874-1893 (Reel 44)
- Reel 45
  - Abstracts of Old Roads, 1650-1852 (Reel 45)
- Reel 46, Student Papers from the James A. Kelly Institute for Historical Studies at St. Francis College, 1958 (Reel 46)
  - Bligh, Thomas F. History of the Press in Brooklyn and Kings County. (Reel 46)
  - Hudson, William. The Flatlands Story. (Reel 46)
  - Green, Thomas R. Inns and Taverns, Their Place in Brooklyn History. (Reel 46)
  - McCarthy, Arthur E. The Assimilation and Integration of Various Groups Coming to Brooklyn. (Reel 46)
- Reel 47
  - Street Index Cards, 1957 (Reel 47)
- Reel 48
  - Laws of County Clerk and Register's Office, circa 1810-1930 (Reel 48)
  - A Memorial of Saint Paul's Church, 1888 (Reel 48)
  - Historic Greenpoint, circa 1940 (Reel 48)
  - Brooklyn Village 1816-1834, 1938 (Reel 48)
  - Historical Sketch of the South Brooklyn Savings Institution, 1924 (Reel 48)
- Reel 49, Student Papers from the James A. Kelly Institute for Historical Studies at St. Francis College, 1958 (Reel 49)
  - Sabbarese, Pasquale Vincent. Catholic Footprints in Brooklyn. (Reel 49)
  - Kennedy, G.A. Growth and Development of the Police Department in the City of Brooklyn 1646-1898. (Reel 49)
  - Gordon, John C. The Brooklyn Bridge. (Reel 49)
  - Reilly, John H. Brooklyn's Contribution to the Six Wars. (Reel 49)
  - Reilly, William F. Manufacturing and Commerce in Brooklyn 1609-1958. (Reel 49)
  - Mannino, Joseph A. Mayors and Borough Presidents of Brooklyn. (Reel 49)
  - Reilly, Thomas G. A History of Brooklyn Ferries Including the Eastern District Ferries 1642-1958. (Reel 49)
  - McCarthy, John B. The Life of Thomas Dongan as Governor of New York. (Reel 49)
  - Randazzo, Joseph S. Old Roads and Highways of Brooklyn. (Reel 49)
  - D'Ambra, Francis N. History of Brooklyn Theater. (Reel 49)
  - Bartlett, Clifford A. The Battle of Brooklyn. (Reel 49)
  - Mastrion, Guy. The City of Williamsburgh 1852-1854. (Reel 49)
  - Sullivan, Lawrence. Thesis on Flatbush and New Lots. (Reel 49)
  - Markham, James Kevin. Athletic Clubs in Brooklyn. (Reel 49)
  - Clancy, Martin. Why Brooklyn Should Not Become a City. (Reel 49)
  - Morgan, William F. Shipbuilding in the Borough of Brooklyn. (Reel 49)
- Reel 50A
  - 175th Anniversary of the Battle of Brooklyn, Commemorative Stamps Scrapbook, 1952 (Reel 50A)
  - Jennie Jerome Scrapbook, 1952 (Reel 50A)
- Reel 50B
  - Jennie Jerome Scrapbook, 1952 (Reel 50B)
  - 175th Anniversary of the Battle of Brooklyn, Commemorative Stamps Scrapbook, 1952 (Reel 50B)
  - Verrazano Rededication Scrapbook, 1924-1952 (Reel 50B)
  - The Tiger, History and Recovery Scrapbook, circa 1945 (Reel 50B)
  - Supervisor Minutes, Volume 1, 1714-1782 (Reel 50B)
  - Supervisor Minutes, Volume 2, 1784-1797 (Reel 50B)
- Reel 51
  - Indian Purchase, 1654 (Reel 51)
  - Supervisor Minutes, Volume 3, 1798-1829 (Reel 51)
  - Flatbush Town Meetings, Town Board, Supervisors Papers, 1817-1894 (Reel 51)
  - Williamsburgh Trustees Minutes, 1827-1832 (Reel 51)
  - Gravesend Book 307 Town Records, 1799-1845 (Reel 51)
- Reel 52
  - Williamsburgh Town Records, Number 5, 1842-1855 (Reel 52)
  - Secret Sessions of Board Alderman, 1835-1860 (Reel 52)
  - Flatlands, Minutes of Town Meetings, 1783-1857 (Reel 52)
  - City of Brooklyn, Ordinances, 1834-1847 (Reel 52)
  - Reports of Commissioners, 1835-1839 (Reel 52)
- Reel 53
  - Index to Marriages Performed by Mayors of Brooklyn, 1839-1887 (Reel 53)
  - Marriage Records (Mayors), 1839-1887 (Reel 53)
  - Marriages in Kings County, 1864-1865 (Reel 53)
  - Records of Bushwick, Flatlands and Flatbush, 1846-1851 (Reel 53)
- Reel 54
  - Williamsburgh Reports of Special and Standing Committees, 1853-1854 (Reel 54)
  - Williamsburgh Reports of Special and Standing Committees, 1854 (Reel 54)
  - Map Index, circa 1680-1850 (Reel 54)
- Reel 55, Student Papers from the James A. Kelly Institute for Historical Studies at St. Francis College, 1959-1961 (Reel 55)
  - Brother Malachy. Brooklyn's Red Hook., 1959 (Reel 55)
  - Wolynez, Melvin. Melrose Hall. (Reel 55)
  - Juliana, Mary. Colonial Dutch Life in Flatbush as Portrayed by the Lott Family., 1961 (Reel 55)
  - Mingione, Joseph. A History of the Gravesend Fisheries., 1960 (Reel 55)
  - Chrysostom, Mary. The Negro in Brooklyn, From Slavery to Freedom., 1960 (Reel 55)
  - Mary Emily. Catholic Childcare in Brooklyn During the 19th Century., 1959 (Reel 55)
  - Joseph, Maureen. Green-Wood Cemetery. (Reel 55)
  - Raymond, Mary. Brooklyn Post Office., 1960 (Reel 55)
  - Monahan, Kenneth. Henry Ward Beecher, Brooklyn Abolitionist, and the Anti-Slavery Movement 1830-1860., 1961 (Reel 55)
  - Jerome, Francis. The Brooklyn Children's Museum, a Community Resource Center., 1961 (Reel 55)
- Reel 56, Student Papers from the James A. Kelly Institute for Historical Studies at St. Francis College, 1961 (Reel 56)
  - Eliphalet Williams Bliss. (Reel 56)